# CAVAN **MITCHELL**

Senior Product Manager Software Developer Entrepreneur



# **ABOUT ME**

Senior Product Manager for over 5 years with 3 years of Front-End Development experience. Projects have market caps that have reached in the millions.

Cavan has multiple entrepreneurial ventures and over 15 years of professional work experience. Raised millions in funds for a variety of projects and believes in giving back to the community.

- $\searrow$ cavan.chan@gmail.com
- 8 702-530-6896
- www.cavanmitchell.com
- github.com/cavan-mitchell

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Javascript** HTML / CSS **Tailwind CSS Data Analytics**  Solidity React JS **Next JS** 

Sanity.io

Magento 2

**DESIGN SKILLS** 

**Photoshop Audacity Powerpoint** 

Wordpress

Premiere Pro **UX** Design Wireframing

# **BUSINESS SKILLS**

AGILE/SCRUM **Problem Solving Marketing & Sales Motivating** 

Servant Leadership **Fund Raising Public Speaking Training** 

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Code Red Agency**

(2021 - Current)

**Product Manager & Front-End Developer** 

My freelance agency that I started prior to the pandemic. We've built both Web2 and Web3 projects but only Web3 projects are listed below. These have hit top 3 trending on Coin Market Cap at least once.

#### **Galaxy Heroes Coin**

dex.galaxyheroescoin.com

~\$300M market cap token. Contracted by Highstack.co to layout UX/UI design that display NFT's. Assisted with search functions in marketplace and displaying search modal. Over \$50M TVL in the staking contracts and \$12M in liquidity. NFT's raised over \$2.5M in sales.

#### Xenon Pay

farm.xenonswap.org

~\$50M market cap token. Assisted with building a staking platform and De-Fi marketplace. \$12M TVL in smart contracts

#### **GWJK Finance**

greenwojak.finance/#buy

Small cap crypto that was launched amongst friends. This token takes taxed amounts, sells them for BNB, and distributes to all holders on an hourly basis. I helped with setting road maps and assisted with UX design.

# **Red Rock Properties LLC**

(2017 - Current)

**Managing Partner** 

- Property Acquisitions in Tennessee and Nevada.
- Converted properties to Short Term Rentals.
- Passively operating Property Management team for the STR's.

#### **Rock & Reilly's Restaurant** Investor/Fund Raiser/Managing Partner

(2018 - Current)

- Implemented NCR Aloha POS system with management team, updated menu items, set loyalty programs, integrated payment systems and created dashboard with KPI metrics for reports.
- Raised \$300,000 start up capital for USC Campus location.
- Co-raised \$1M for Downtown Los Angeles location.

#### Fair-Klima Capital

(2012 - 2016)

**Senior Product Manager** 

Company products include P2P lending platform, mobile apps & mobile gaming development. Previous company size 250 employees.

- Lead Cross Functional Team of 30 people consisted of Back-end Developers, Front-end Developers, UX Designer and Copywriters
- Implemented Agile management practices with code sprints and daily standup meetings. Problem solved impediments and pushed team updates via Jira.
- Created product roadmaps, user stories and visual boards to guide team leading to a solid track record of delivery.
- Directly interacted and provided updates to stakeholders.
- Established targeted KPI's and pushed data driven approach which increased traffic, user sign up and engagement.
- Used Scrum methodology to develop mobile apps for large conferences and natively installed in Samsung tablets.
- Organized and facilitated planning, scrum ceremonies and optimizations of backlogs for 3 teams simultaneously.

#### Projects that remain today.

www.boaoforum.org www.51give.org www.51sim.ora www.cncf.ora.cn

# CAVAN MITCHELL

#### **EDUCATION**

Florida International University Bachelor in Finance - Class of 2002

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

Chinese



#### **HOBBIES**

Co-founded Right to Succeed Foundation a 501(c)3 not-for-profit organization that positively impacted thousands of students. www.righttosucceed.org/about

Member of Toastmaster an organization to improve communication and public speaking.

# **FUN FACTS**

Cavan placed 53rd out of 30,000 entrees in the World Series of Poker. https://tinyurl.com/yptxcz3z

Help launched a recording artist known as Deb's Daughter that reached #1 on the Billboards Chart in 2017. https://tinyurl.com/mubn4m86

Lead Coordinator of Major Tennis Charity Event featuring Novak Djokovic and Li Na. Attendance broke records with over 13,000 people and was viewed by over 100M people via national televised broadcast and streaming video platforms. https://tinyurl.com/24wz2b4p

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Superior Bud**

(2016 - 2019)\*

Investor/Fund Raiser/Managing Partner

- Raised \$1M to operate a total of 5 Indoor cultivation facilities.
- In charge of all aspects of operations including hiring staff, marketing, procurement and quality control.
- Cash out exit prior to California becoming full recreational.

# **Cygroup Trading**

(2010 - 2012)

Partner/Marketing

Proprietary stock trading firm offering educational services and wholesale trading with up to 20x leverage.

- Co-developed high volume trading strategies targeting rebates on specific trading routes.
- Onboarding new traders and students via marketing efforts.

Zongshen Motorcycle (North America) (2003 - 2008) Finance Manager -> Vice President

Manufacturer of vehicles with 18,000+ employees worldwide. U.S based office in charge of North and South American markets with 10 employees.

- Expanded distribution channels to North and South America.
- Managed day to day operations, working with big box retailers and registering vehicles with DOT and EPA compliance.